Guide to the Division of Student Affairs Reference Collection, 1987-2019 UA.01.11.0051
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Division of Student Affairs Reference collection
1987-2019
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0051
1 Linear Feet
The mission of the Division of Student Affairs is to promote and enrich students' education through teaching, mentoring, advising, and counseling by way of on-going direct contact with students in their everyday lives. The division was created in the summer of 1979 and was placed in under the supervision of William J. Griffiths, Vice President for Student Affairs. This collection contains reports, department newsletters, and materials related to the Center for Sexual and Gender Diversity, student activities, student health, and career planning.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Division of Student Affairs Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Historical Note
The mission of the Division of Student Affairs is to promote and enrich students' education through teaching, mentoring, advising, and counseling by way of on-going direct contact with students in their every day lives. The division was created in the summer of 1979 and was placed in under the supervision of William J. Griffiths, Vice President for Student Affairs. Griffith retired in 1991 and was succeeded by Janet S. Dickerson. Jim Clack became interim Vice President for Student Affairs when Janet Dickerson left in July of 2000 for Princeton University. The current (2011) Vice President of Student Affairs, Larry Moneta, accepted the position in 2001.
Student Affairs is comprised of a multitude of departments, all of which work in tandem to support and enrich students' educational experiences during their time at Duke University. These departments include: Campus Life; Career Center; Counseling and Psychological Services (CAPS); Dean of Students Office; Residence Life and Housing Services; Student Health Center; and Resource Administration.
Related Material
Career Center Office records, 1938-2000
University Archives, Duke University.
Community Service Center records, 1990-[ongoing].
University Archives, Duke University.
Division of Student Affairs. Office of Student Activities Records, 1939-1993
University Archives, Duke University
Fraternity and Sorority Life records, 1984-2003.
University Archives, Duke University.
Freeman Center for Jewish Life, 1987-2000.
University Archives, Duke University.
International House records, 1957-[ongoing].
University Archives, Duke University.
Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Task Force records, 1991-1998.
University Archives, Duke University
Office of Residential Life Records, 1946-2000 and undated.
University Archives, Duke University.
Office of Student Activities and Facilities records, c.1936-1992.
University Archives, Duke University.
Office of Student Activities and Facilities Reference Collection, 1936-[ongoing].
University Archives, Duke University.
Women's Center records, 1984-2002.
University Archives, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The Division of Student Life Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. It includes an administrative history of the Division of Student Affairs, East Campus enhancement reports; Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Task Force reports; and other committee reports regarding Greek life and student affairs. Contains various department newsletters, manuals, directories, and publications. Also includes materials related to the Center for Sexual and Gender Diversity and career planning.
Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University; Duke University. Division of Student Affairs; Duke University. Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender Task Force.
- Administrative history, 1979 (Box 1)
- Student affairs memoranda and flyers, 1962-1998 (Box 1)
- Letter to Parents / Janet S. Dickerson, 1995 (Box 1)
- Clippings- administration and personnel, 1991-2001 (Box 1)
- Clippings, 1967-1985 (Box 1)
- Student Activities newsletter, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
- Faculty-in-Residence directories, 1996 or 1997 (Box 1)
- Directory of Student Organizations/Student Activities, approximately 1936-1938 (Box 1)
- Directory of Organizations, approximately 1973-1977 (Box 1)
- Student Organizations, Duke University, 1968-1976 (Box 1)
- Student activities: brochures, lists, 1969-1991 (Box 1)
- Student activities: manuals and instructions for student organizations, 1970s-1983 (Box 1)
- Activities Calendar Handbook, 1978 (Box 1)
- Student Education Project, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
- Student Activities Leadership Assistance Program / Provost Agreement, 1984 (Box 1)
- Student Labor Services, 1975-1986 (Box 1)
- Advising Information Directory, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Appointments Office, undated (Box 2)
- Career planning, 1979-1984 (Box 2)
- Career planning- apprenticeships, approximately 1976-1989 (Box 2)
- Career planning- conferences, 1980 (Box 2)
- Career Development Center, 1990-1993 (Box 2)
- Career Center, 1999 (Box 2)
- Center for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Life, approximately 1996-1999 (Box 2)
- Center for Sexual and Gender Diversity: Duke P.R.I.D.E. Training booklet, approximately 2017 (Box 2)
- Center for Sexual and Gender Diversity: Trans 101 training booklet, 2019; 2022 (Box 2)
- International House, 1992-2000 (Box 2)
- Judicial Board, 1958-1979 (Box 2)
- Student health, 1973-1997 (Box 2)
- Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual Task Force Reports, 1991-92, 1992-93, 1993-94, 1995-96 (Box 2)
- Task Force on Greek Life Report, 1994 (Box 2)
- Grounds Committee Task Force (Quad Squad), 1987 (Box 2)
- East Campus Enhancement Committee, Report, 1994 (Box 2)
- Report of the committee for Investigation and Recommendation on Student Affairs, 1934 (Box 2)
- Duke publications, 2008-2009; 2016 (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Publications contain articles about the Center for Sexual and Gender Diversity. Includes Duke Magazine, March-April 2008; GIST magazine, Spring 2009, Vol. 3, issue 1; and Divinity, Fall 2016.